CARLOS GARCÍA

PYTHON JR BACKEND DEVELOPER

Cl65B. #88-59 Bogotá D.C

+57-320-702-1833 carlos.grh@outlook.com



HTTPS://CARLOS-GARCIA-RESUME.HEROKUAPP.COM

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am an Accounts Receivable professional with over 4 years of experience in portfolio collections and credit analysis. I am driven through experience and knowledge, always wanting to go above what's expected. My goals are to become a subject matter expert in whatever role I have and obtain results the right way. I am also an excellent team player having received numerous recognition for my work from peers and stakeholders. Looking to shift my career as an Accounts Receivable Specialist to a Python Backend Developer.

SOFT SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILL

Analytical Innovative Python Django Flask Decisiveness Self-starter/Self-learning MySQL PowerBi English C1

Continous learning

WORK EXPERIENCE

Strategic Planning Collector Iron Mountain, Bogota D.C

Mar, 2022- Present

- Handle top sales accounts with risk of suspension portfolio.
- Handle the bi-weekly meeting with the Customer Success Managers and Directors to discuss dispute resolution of high-risk customers.
- Develop and innovate repetitive processes with Python to automize pain points redirecting the focus of tasks for collectors to more impactful analytical processes.
- Project Proposal for with Collections VP, Vertical Manager, and Collections Ops Director for automation through Python of collections communication, mass statements with letters specified for preventive collections, delinquent customers and risk of credit hold.

Credit Service Representative Medtronic SSC, Bogota D.C

Sep, 2019 - Mar, 2022

- Review/create account general information to avoid duplicate accounts for billing/shipping errors.
- Review financial statements of LATAM accounts to suggest a credit limit modification.
- Establish/implement the standard operating procedures for the collections and credit analysis teams.
- Review and implement collection strategies to reduce past due AR.
- Review blocked orders and provide solutions to customer disputes.
- Maintain good customer contact relationship for preventive collections.
- · Work collectively with the sales team in order to obtain payment from difficult customers and avoid suspensions/credit holds.
- Initially handled the Endovenous West portfolio and later the Government portfolio with a total of over 15M USD each.
- Developed SAP PR1 Scripts integrated with Excel VBA in order to automize invoice download.

Python Novice Blog (www.pythonnoviceblog.com)

July, 2022 - Present

Aug, 2022

Self project

- Build a simple frontend with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Use Django Framework to build database models.
- Create views and templates with Python and Django's view controller and template language to create a website interface.
- User SQL relational models for users, user comments, user likes, blog posts, and user profiles.
- · Version control through GIT using GIT bash commands.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete SQL and MySQL Course - From Beginner to Expert Udemy

• Data Types

- Create Databases
- Insert, remove and update items/tables
- SELECT, WHERE, AND, Wildcards
- ORDER BY & GROUP BY

- Relational models, Inner Join, Left and right Join
- Normalization
- Subqueries
- Commit, Rollback, Savepoints
- Indexes and constraints
- Variables, loops and B tree DS

100 days of code: The Complete Python Pro Bootcamp 2022 Udemy

PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab

- Python Scripting and Automation
- Web Scraping
- Beautiful Soup
- Selenium Web Driver
- Request
- Python GUI Desktop App Development
- Bash Command Line
- Git, GitHub and Version Control

Feb, 2022- Apr, 2022

- Databases
- SQL
- SQLite
- PostgreSQL

REFERENCES

Edward Mojica | Credit & Collections Manager at Medtronic Cell: +57 321 2158866 Email: edward.mojica@medtronic.com

Carlos Borja | Model Design and Best Practices Manager at Scotiabank Cell: +57 301 2812329 Email: carlosb.urz@gmail.com